Summary

Mobile engineer with around 9 years of experience mainly in building scalable iOS software for a wide range of businesses ranging from Augmented Reality to Financial Services and have served millions of users. Currently looking for a challenging new contract role in Amsterdam and some fun people to work with. I have been living in the Netherlands for more than 5 years now and can speak some Dutch as well:)

App Showcase

Moneyou Go

iPhone, iPod Touch

One of the best mobile banking solutions in NL and DE

March 2018 - December 2018

2dehands.be

iPhone, iPod Touch, iPad

Largest B2C and C2C Marketplace in Belgium

June 2016 - December 2017

Upcoming Visual Search, Object Recognition and Augmented Reality platform

iPhone, iPod Touch, iPad June 2015 - May 2016

iPhone, iPod Touch, iPad

World leading and pioneering Augmented Reality Platform

November 2014 - May 2016

Jumbo E-commerce app for Jumbo Supermarket

iPhone, iPod Touch February 2014 - November 2014

Recent Work Experience

Moneyou

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

Senior iOS Engineer - Freelance

March 2018 - December 2018

- Help Moneyou team with their iOS Feature development and release
- Setup test automation for iOS
- Won moneyou hackathon and successfully implemented suggested features in the app
- Helped in creating a banking infrastructure with AWS Serverless Lambdas

Veon

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

January 2018 - February 2018

Senior iOS Engineer - Freelance

- Short term contract to help with refactoring of VEON iOS App
- Improve continuous integration for iOS

Ebay Inc.

Amsterdam, The Netherlands June 2016 - December 2017

Senior iOS Engineer - Freelance

- Singlehandedly maintain and develop the 2dehands.be App for Belgium that has millions of users
- Also spent some time as part of the ebay global mobile team building classified apps for 11 different countries for example Gumtree UK
- Setup all required processes for iOS software development such as Automated Testing, Continuous Integration, Crash Analysis etc.

Layar

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

Senior iOS Engineer

November 2014 - May 2016

- Lead Developer for the iOS Layar App that makes millions of users see Augmented Reality
- Lead Developer for the iOS Lavar SDK that help businesses make Augmented Reality solutions

 Part of the team building the Blippar App that makes people visually search from the world around them

IceMobile Agency

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

Senior iOS Engineer

February 2014 - November 2014

- Senior engineer in the iOS development team building apps for the leading supermarkets in the Netherlands such as Jumbo and Albert Heijn
- Gathering business requirements and coming up with efficient technical solutions to address them
- Automating user interface testing and setting up continuous integration

Ebuddy

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

iOS Developer June 2013 - January 2014

- Working in the iOS Development Team building the messaging app XMS that had millions of users around the world and was a competitor to watsapp

Previous Work Experience

Simple Apps LLC

New Delhi, India

Founder February 2012 - June 2013

- Started an iOS App development company and built several apps under it

Self Employed *iOS Consultant*

New Delhi, India

May 2012 - June 2013

Stayed at home in India with parents and helped various companies around the world with their iOS development and design. My clients were based in Singapore, Florida, North Carolina, Washington DC, Israel among other places.

MicroStrategy Inc.

McLean,VA

Software Engineer

September 2010 - January 2012

- Worked on several iOS Development projects for the clients of Microstrategy and helped automate various tasks. Also helped develop the microstrategy SDK. iOS was a pretty new technology at this point so this was some really good experience.

Citisync.com

Gainesville.FL

iOS Developer

January 2010- July 2010

- Singlehandedly built the citisync iOS Application. This was when iOS 3 was the latest version. Also my first experience as an iOS Developer and it piqued my interest in the field

University of Florida, Department of Emergency Medicine

Gainesville,FL

Java Developer

September 2009 - February 2010

 Together with the resident doctors, developed a board game with Java Swing that helped medical students learn in an interactive manner

Bloomberg LP

New York,NY

Financial Software Development Intern

May 2009 - August 2009

- As an intern I helped out with a number of projects in the Global Trading team writing code in C++ and managing large mainframe supercomputers

Education

University of Florida

Gaineville,FL

Masters in Computer Engineering

August 2008 - August 2010

- CGPA: 3.6/4.0

Skills

Languages: Objective C, Swift, C, C++, Python, Bash, Javascript

Technical Skills: Test Driven Development, Automated UI Testing, Continuous Integration Setup (Jenkins/Teamcity), Rapid iOS prototyping, GIT, Xcode, iOS Security (ATS), Machine learning, Restful API Design

Business Skills: Agile/Scrum Development, Managing Expectations, Project Estimation, Converting Business Goals to Technical Requirements, Risk Management

Other Interests

General Aviation, Hiking, Travel, Salsa Dancing, Poker, Billiards.